Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/sethisilky (LinkedIn) www.zsassociates.com/ (Other)

Top Skills

Talent Acquisition
Human Resources
Screening

Languages

Marathi (Elementary)
Punjabi (Native or Bilingual)
English (Full Professional)

Silky Sethi

Hiring Data Scientists at ZS Bengaluru

Summary

Having been part of this enthralling Human Resources community for over 5 years, I have been lucky to be a part of various HR functions like Recruiting, Learning & Development and Human Resources Operations. As I enjoyed different phases of HR, I must mention that I had more inclination towards Recruiting and hence, I chose to pursue my career in this dynamic and ever-evolving function.

I feel proud to be associated with the most talented, focused, yet funloving recruiting team of ZS. It has been an enriching experience to interact with amazingly talented professionals and experts of the advanced analytics and data science industry. I thoroughly enjoy finding, recruiting and hiring crème de la crème Data Scientists and advanced analytics geeks who have an incredible contribution in the growth of the firm.

When I am not recruiting, you would find me cooking for my loved ones, treating myself with some good music or a sound sleep!

My Expertise: Recruiting for Advanced Analytics and Data Science roles, Tier-1 Campus recruiting (IITs, NITs, BITs), Stakeholder Management, formulating recruiting strategy, Employer Branding focused on Data Science track at ZS, Planning & executing gamification events in data science etc.

Currently hiring for Data Scientists having experience in: Machine learning, NLP, Text Mining, Predictive Analytics or Real World Evidence (RWE) who are ready to work across our state-of-the-art offices in India (Pune & New Delhi). Feel free to reach out to me at silky.sethi@zs.com

Experience

ZS Associates

6 years 10 months

Recruiting Specialist July 2019 - Present (1 year 2 months) Bengaluru Area, India

Senior Recruiter January 2016 - Present (4 years 8 months) Pune Area, India

Associates (www.zsassociates.com) ZS is the world's largest firm focused exclusively on helping companies improve overall performance and grow revenue and market share, through end-to-end sales and marketing solutions – from customer insights and strategy to analytics, operations and technology. More than 5,000 ZS professionals in 22 offices worldwide draw on deep industry and domain expertise to deliver impact for clients across multiple industries.

ZS' India Capability and Expertise Centers house more than 60% of ZS people across two locations based in Pune and Gurgaon. Our teams work in conjunction with onshore colleagues to deliver our sales and marketing projects to our clients. The Centers primarily support client projects based in North America, Europe and East Asia in the areas of Business Analysis, Business Operations and Business Technology.

In my current role, I focus on hiring Data Scientists across all levels for our India CECs. This involves designing and executing recruiting strategies across Tier-1 Campuses (University hiring) as well as in-market hiring channels. I am actively involved in stakeholder management by ensuring timely interactions with hiring managers to understand these niche requirements, provide frequent touch points on hiring progress, act as a subject matter expert and recommend the most appropriate recruiting methodologies leading to an effective turnover. I also mentor and guide the team members as and when required to implement effective recruiting strategies and processes to ensure high level of service delivery in the entire recruiting function. I strive towards being 100% process compliant, follow strict protocols during interview rounds, adhere to a systematic approach while using applicant tracking systems and other HR systems. I actively participate in various firm initiatives which helps in making recruiting more optimised in terms of cost, time & resources; Ensuring a top-notch candidate experience.

Recruiter
November 2013 - December 2015 (2 years 2 months)

Key responsibilities included-

- •End to end recruitment across all the levels within Business Consulting Capability group along with few positions in the Business Operations and Enterprise support function (HR). Work closely with Hiring Managers to develop position profile and to understand overall needs and requirements. (Description, salary, timing, expectations, etc).
- •Sourcing candidates through Social networking sites, Job Portals, Applicant Tracking System, Referrals and Networks within the Industry.
- Stakeholder Management
- Negotiate salaries and present offers and close selected candidates
- •Been successful in recruitment and Hiring for all levels with minimal vendor engagement

Thyssenkrupp Electrical Steel India Pvt Ltd Human Resources Officer May 2012 - February 2013 (10 months) Nashik, India

Key responsibilities-

- •Hiring engineers from entry level to Managerial level across all the departments for ist Nashik plant. Facilitating the on-boarding and joining formalities for all the joiners.
- •Maintaining the records of Training Needs of all the employees across the departments. Planing training programs (Technical as well as Soft Skills/Behavioural) for the staff as well as workers as per the needs identified.
- •Setting up training calendars for the employees across the departments.
- •Conducting Training Effectiveness Evaluation from the concerned Heads of the departments for the training imparted to their employees.

Taj Hotels Resorts and Palaces Human Resources Supervisor January 2009 - July 2010 (1 year 7 months) Pune

- •End to end recruitment across the levels for the Business Unit in Pune
- •Responsible for all disciplinary actions in accordance with the laws including issuing warning letters, termination, suspension etc.
- •Implement Employee Satisfaction surveys & ensure the results are communicated & follow up on the action plans
- Orientation and induction for new joiner

•Driving reward & recognition system & Corporate Social Responsibility initiatives at the unit

Education

Indsearch Insitute of Management Studies
Post Graduation Diploma in Business Management, Human
Resources · (2010 - 2012)

University of Pune

Bachelor of Commerce (BCom), Business/Commerce, General · (2007 - 2010)